import NES1 from "./NES1.mp4"
import NES2 from "./NES2.mp4"
import NES3 from "./NES3.mp4"
import NES4 from "./NES4.mp4"
import NES5 from "./NES5.mp4"
import NES6 from "./NES6.mp4"
import NES7 from "./NES7.mp4"
import NES8 from "./NES8.mp4"
import NES9 from "./NES9.mp4"
import NES10 from "./NES10.mp4"
import NES11 from "./NES11.mp4"
import NES12 from "./NES12.mp4"
import NES13 from "./NES13.mp4"
import NES14 from "./NES14.mp4"
import NES15 from "./NES15.mp4"
import NES16 from "./NES16.mp4"
import NES17 from "./NES17.mp4"
import NES18 from "./NES18.mp4"
import NES19 from "./NES19.mp4"
import NES20 from "./NES20.mp4"
import NES21 from "./NES21.mp4"
import NES22 from "./NES22.mp4"
import NES23 from "./NES23.mp4"
import NES24 from "./NES24.mp4"
import NES25 from "./NES25.mp4"
import NES26 from "./NES26.mp4"
import NES27 from "./NES27.mp4"
import NES28 from "./NES28.mp4"
import NES29 from "./NES29.mp4"
import NES30 from "./NES30.mp4"
import NES31 from "./NES31.mp4"
import NES32 from "./NES32.mp4"
import NES33 from "./NES33.mp4"
import NES34 from "./NES34.mp4"
import NES35 from "./NES35.mp4"
import NES36 from "./NES36.mp4"
import NES37 from "./NES37.mp4"
import NES38 from "./NES38.mp4"
import NES39 from "./NES39.mp4"
import NES40 from "./NES40.mp4"
import NES41 from "./NES41.mp4"
import NES42 from "./NES42.mp4"
import NES43 from "./NES43.mp4"
import NES44 from "./NES44.mp4"
import NES45 from "./NES45.mp4"
import NES46 from "./NES46.mp4"
import NES47 from "./NES47.mp4"
import NES48 from "./NES48.mp4"
import NES49 from "./NES49.mp4"
import NES50 from "./NES50.mp4"
import NES51 from "./NES51.mp4"
import NES52 from "./NES52.mp4"
import NES53 from "./NES53.mp4"
import NES54 from "./NES54.mp4"
import NES55 from "./NES55.mp4"

export const nest = [
    {
        id: 472,
        videoFile: NES55,
        rusQuestion: "кроткий , смиренный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "quiet, gentle, and not willing to argue or express your opinions in a forceful way:",
        answer: "meek",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 471,
        videoFile: NES54,
        rusQuestion: "палата , сторожить",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "one of the parts or large rooms into which a hospital is divided, usually with beds for patients:",
        answer: "ward",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 470,
        videoFile: NES53,
        rusQuestion: "морщинистый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(of skin) having small lines because of old age :",
        answer: "wrinkled",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 469,
        videoFile: NES52,
        rusQuestion: "ствол дерева",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the thick main stem of a tree, from which its branches grow",
        answer: "tree trunk",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 468,
        videoFile: NES50,
        rusQuestion: "ватты",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the standard measure of electrical power:",
        answer: "watt",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 467,
        videoFile: NES49,
        rusQuestion: "жидкость",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a substance that flows and is not solid:",
        answer: "fluid",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 466,
        videoFile: NES48,
        rusQuestion: "хитрый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "deceiving people in a clever way in order to get what you want:",
        answer: "sly",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 465,
        videoFile: NES47,
        rusQuestion: "кругленькая сумма",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(of amounts of money) large:",
        answer: "tidy",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 464,
        videoFile: NES46,
        rusQuestion: "размышляя",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "making you feel uncomfortable or worried, as if something bad is going to happen:",
        answer: "brooding",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 463,
        videoFile: NES45,
        rusQuestion: "кабриолет",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a car with a soft roof that can be folded back:",
        answer: "convertible",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 462,
        videoFile: NES44,
        rusQuestion: "я не обязан",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "loyal and willing to give your time and energy to something that you believe in:",
        answer: "committed",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 461,
        videoFile: NES43,
        rusQuestion: "чрезмерно",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "too; very:",
        answer: "overly",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 460,
        videoFile: NES42,
        rusQuestion: "нос корабля",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the front part of a ship",
        answer: "bow",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 459,
        videoFile: NES41,
        rusQuestion: "кормовой",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the back part of a ship or boat:",
        answer: "stern",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 458,
        videoFile: NES40,
        rusQuestion: "они снова отправят тебя в банку",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a closed metal container, especially cylinder-shaped, in which some types of drink and food are sold:",
        answer: "can",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 457,
        videoFile: NES39,
        rusQuestion: "государственное психиатрическое учреждение",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "w",
        answer: "state mental institution",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 456,
        videoFile: NES38,
        rusQuestion: "выйти вперед",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(idiomatic, dated) To go faster; to hurry up",
        answer: "get the lead out",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 455,
        videoFile: NES37,
        rusQuestion: "забор",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a structure that divides two areas of land, similar to a wall but made of wood or wire and supported with posts",
        answer: "fence",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 454,
        videoFile: NES36,
        rusQuestion: "мох",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a very small, green or yellow plant that grows especially in wet earth or on rocks, walls, and tree trunks:",
        answer: "moss",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 453,
        videoFile: NES35,
        rusQuestion: "пошутить над кем-то",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to joke with someone by saying something that is hard for the person to believe:",
        answer: "put someone on",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 452,
        videoFile: NES34,
        rusQuestion: "сфальсифицированный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to arrange dishonestly for the result of something, for example an election, to be changed:",
        answer: "rigged",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 451,
        videoFile: NES32,
        rusQuestion: "отложен",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to have a pause or rest during a formal meeting or trial:",
        answer: "adjourned",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 450,
        videoFile: NES31,
        rusQuestion: "раздавится как баклажан",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to crush something into a flat shape: an oval, purple vegetable that is white inside and is usually eaten cooked",
        answer: "squash like a eggplant",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 449,
        videoFile: NES30,
        rusQuestion: "продолжить",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to continue as planned:",
        answer: "proceed",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 448,
        videoFile: NES29,
        rusQuestion: "разнообразие",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a different type of something:",
        answer: "variety",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 447,
        videoFile: NES28,
        rusQuestion: "завести часы",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "To oooo a mechanical device is to cause it to work by turning a key or handle.",
        answer: "to wind",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 446,
        videoFile: NES27,
        rusQuestion: "чемпион",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "informal for champion",
        answer: "champ",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 445,
        videoFile: NES26,
        rusQuestion: "селитра",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a salty-tasting white powder used to preserve meat, and also used in producing explosives and fertilizers (= substances that help plants grow)",
        answer: "saltpeter",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 444,
        videoFile: NES25,
        rusQuestion: "дрочить",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a rude phrase meaning to masturbate",
        answer: "jerk off",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 443,
        videoFile: NES24,
        rusQuestion: "всемогущий",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(of God) having the power to do everything:",
        answer: "almighty",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 442,
        videoFile: NES23,
        rusQuestion: "кто подает",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a throw in a baseball game:",
        answer: "pitching",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 441,
        videoFile: NES22,
        rusQuestion: "разорен",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "broken: caught or arrested by the police for doing something illegal:",
        answer: "busted",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 440,
        videoFile: NES21,
        rusQuestion: "соответствовать его удару",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to hit or throw something using force:",
        answer: "whang",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 439,
        videoFile: NES20,
        rusQuestion: "таблицы",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to show information in the form of a table (= an arrangement of facts and numbers in rows or blocks)",
        answer: "tabulate",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 438,
        videoFile: NES19,
        rusQuestion: "неограничительный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "not limiting the freedom of someone, or the size or meaning of something:",
        answer: "nonrestrictive",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 437,
        videoFile: NES18,
        rusQuestion: "отдых",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(a way of) enjoying yourself when you are not working:",
        answer: "recreation",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 436,
        videoFile: NES17,
        rusQuestion: "вождь",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "most important or main:",
        answer: "chief",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
     {
        id: 435,
        videoFile: NES16,
        rusQuestion: "чепуха , вздор",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "nonsense:",
        answer: "baloney",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 434,
        videoFile: NES15,
        rusQuestion: "отпусти ее",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to free someone or something; to remove anything that limits the freedom of action of someone or something:",
        answer: "turn her loose",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 433,
        videoFile: NES14,
        rusQuestion: "аллюзии",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a brief or indirect reference: something that is said or written that is intended to make you think of a particular thing or person:",
        answer: "allusion",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 432,
        videoFile: NES13,
        rusQuestion: "странный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "having or relating to a gender identity or a sexuality that does not fit society's traditional ideas about gender or sexuality:",
        answer: "queer",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 431,
        videoFile: NES12,
        rusQuestion: "своеобразный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "unusual and strange, sometimes in an unpleasant way:",
        answer: "peculiar",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 430,
        videoFile: NES11,
        rusQuestion: "сопоставление",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the fact of putting things that are not similar next to each other:",
        answer: "juxtaposition",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 429,
        videoFile: NES10,
        rusQuestion: "размышлял",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to form opinions about something without having the necessary information or facts; to make guesses:to guess possible answers to a question when you do not have enough information to be certain:",
        answer: "speculate",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 428,
        videoFile: NES9,
        rusQuestion: "в другом месте , на стороне",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "at, in, from, or to another place or other places; anywhere or somewhere else:",
        answer: "elsewhere",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 427,
        videoFile: NES8,
        rusQuestion: "привлекла взгляды мужчин",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to cause something to last longer than is usual or necessary:",
        answer: "she drew stares from man",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 426,
        videoFile: NES7,
        rusQuestion: "определения",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the process of finding something out:",
        answer: "determination",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 425,
        videoFile: NES6,
        rusQuestion: "Я чудо современной науки",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to show or experience great surprise or admiration:",
        answer: "marvel",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 424,
        videoFile: NES5,
        rusQuestion: "сумасшедший",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a person whose behaviour is strange and different from that of most people",
        answer: "wacko",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 423,
        videoFile: NES4,
        rusQuestion: "бобер",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "an animal with smooth fur, sharp teeth, and a large, flat tail. Beavers build dams (= walls of sticks and earth) across rivers.",
        answer: "beaver",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 422,
        videoFile: NES3,
        rusQuestion: "зашивание",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a piece of cloth that is being or needs to be sewn:",
        answer: "sewing shut",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 421,
        videoFile: NES2,
        rusQuestion: "выглядела на 30",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "used for saying that someone behaves like a much older person:",
        answer: "going on for",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 420,
        videoFile: NES1,
        rusQuestion: "установленный законом",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "decided or controlled by law:",
        answer: "statutory",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        getHight: 1
    },
]